<OrdResCollection>
  <OrdRes><OrdResNumber>Ord.</OrdResNumber> <OrdResNumber>No.</OrdResNumber> <OrdResNumber>19-15.</OrdResNumber> <Parties>By</Parties> <Parties>Council</Parties> <Parties>Members</Parties> <Parties>Pruitt</Parties> <Parties>and</Parties> <Parties>Kelley</Parties> <Parties>(by</Parties> <Parties>departmental</Parties> <Parties>request).</Parties> <Junk>an</Junk> <Junk>emergency</Junk> <Junk>ordinance</Junk> <Junk>authorizing</Junk> <Junk>the</Junk> <Junk>Director</Junk> <Junk>of</Junk> <Junk>Public</Junk> <Junk>Utilities</Junk> <Junk>to</Junk> <Junk>make</Junk> <Junk>alterations</Junk> <Junk>and</Junk> <Junk>modifications</Junk> <Junk>in</Junk> <Junk>Contract</Junk> <Junk>No.</Junk> <Junk>CT</Junk> <Junk>2004</Junk> <Junk>PI</Junk> <Junk>2013-18</Junk> <Junk>with</Junk> <Junk>Hooper</Junk> <Junk>Corporation</Junk> <Junk>for</Junk> <Junk>the</Junk> <Junk>Lake</Junk> <Junk>Road</Junk> <Junk>Improvement</Junk> <Junk>for</Junk> <Junk>Phase</Junk> <Junk>3</Junk> <Junk>of</Junk> <Junk>the</Junk> <Junk>Substation</Junk> <Junk>and</Junk> <Junk>Distribution</Junk> <Junk>Expansion</Junk> <Junk>Project</Junk></OrdRes>
  <OrdRes><OrdResNumber>Ord. No. 20-15</OrdResNumber> <Parties>By Council Members K. Johnson and Kelley (by departmental request)</Parties> <Junk>An emergency ordinance to supplement the Codified Ordinances of Cleveland, Ohio, 1976, to enact new Section 131.37; and to amend Section 131.35, amended by Ordinance No. 45914, passed June 9, 2014, relating to rental of League Park Baseball Field and Visitors Center. Whereas, this ordinance constitutes an emergency measure providing for the usual daily operation of a municipal department; now, therefore, Be it ordained by the Council of the City of Cleveland: Section 1. That the Codified Ordinances of Cleveland, Ohio, 1976, are supplemented by enacting new Section 131.37 to read as follows: Section 131.37 Rental of League Park Baseball Field and League Park Visitors Center; Fee (a) The Director of Public Works, or his or her designee, may rent the League Park Baseball Field or the Visitors Center, collectively known as the League Park Complex, when available, as long as a permit is secured under Section 131.07 and the fees specified in this section are paid. Rentals secured under this section shall be for a minimum base rental period of four hours and include setup, event, dismantle, exit of the organizers and their participants and guests, and general clean-up of the rented area. (b) The Director, or his or her designee, shall assess and collect the following fees and charges for the rental of the following: (1) League Park Baseball Field rental: A. Not-For-Profit rental: 1. $300.00 for the base rental period of four hours 2. $37.50 for each half hour the event extends beyond the four-hour base rental period, and any remaining minutes past any half-hour increment shall be prorated using the rate of $37.50 per half hour B. For-Profit rental: 1. $600.00 for the base rental period of four hours 2. $75.00 for each half hour the event extends beyond the four-hour base rental period, and any remaining minutes past any half-hour increment shall be prorated using the rate of $75.00 per half hour (2) League Park Visitors Center rental: A. Not-For-Profit rental: 1. $340.00 for the base rental period of four hours 2. $42.50 for each half hour the event extends beyond the base rental period of four hours, and any remaining minutes past a half-hour increment shall be prorated at the rate of $42.50 per half hour B. For-Profit rental: 1. $400.00 for the base rental period of four hours 2. $50.00 for each half hour the event extends beyond the base rental period of four hours, and any remaining minutes past a half-hour increment shall be prorated at the rate of $50.00 per half hour (c) The party renting either portion of the League Park Complex is  The City Record responsible for general clean-up of the area. (d) Rentals are to conclude 30 minutes before dusk. (e) All fees are due and payable prior to the issuance of a permit. (f) In cases where off-duty commissioned officers or private security services are determined to be necessary by the Director, or his or her designee, it is the responsibility of the party renting either portion of the League Park Complex to provide the services, using a security service approved by the Director, or his or her designee. (g) Any party renting either portion of the League Park Complex is responsible for damages incurred during the rental period and will be required to provide one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) liability and property damage insurance and include the City of Cleveland as an additional insured. (h) Any party renting either portion of the League Park Complex will be required to provide emergency medical personnel for any athletic competition or other event as determined to be necessary by the Director, or his or her designee. (i) All proceeds from gate collections will go to the party renting the facility. (j) All concessions will be operated by the City of Cleveland or its designated vendor. (k) The Director shall deposit the fees and charges collected for the rental of either portion of the League Park Complex into the fund or funds designated to pay the costs of the general operation of the Complex, the equipment and maintenance costs associated with maintaining the Complex, and for improvements to the Complex. The funds collected may be used for and are appropriated for these purposes. (l) After securing the necessary permit under Section 131.07 of these Codified Ordinances, the Director, or his or her designee, may allow the Cleveland Metropolitan School District to rent the baseball field for games or practices, without being assessed the fees and charges specified in division (b) of this section. Section 2. That Section 131.35 of the Codified Ordinances of Cleveland, Ohio, 1976, as amended by Ordinance No. 459-14, passed June 9, 2014, is amended to read as follows: Section 131.35 Rental of Athletic Complexes; Fee (a) The Director of Public Works, or his or her designee, may rent the Collinwood Athletic Complex, the Morgana Athletic Complex, and any other City of Cleveland athletic complexes, when available, as long as a permit is secured under Section 131.07 and the fees specified in this section are paid. This section shall not apply to the rental of the League Park Complex which is subject to the provisions of Section 131.37. (b) The Director, or his or her designee, shall assess and collect the following fees and charges for the rental of athletic complexes: (1) Athletic complex base rental: one thousand dollars ($1,000.00); A. Base rental of the complex is based on a six (6) hour period. B. The six (6) hour base rental period includes set up, event, dismantle, and the exit of the organizers and their participants and guests, and general clean-up.  5  5 C. Each additional hour or fraction thereof exceeding the six (6) hour base rental will cost an additional two hundred dollars ($200.00) per hour. D. During the six (6) hour base rental, if lights are required during any portion of the sporting or athletic event, an additional one hundred dollars ($100.00) per hour or fraction thereof will be charged at the time the permit is issued. The City will bill for any additional lighting costs at one hundred fifty dollars ($150.00) per hour or fraction thereof. E. Party renting the complex is responsible for general clean-up of the area. (2) All fees are due and payable prior to the issuance of a permit. (3) Rentals not requiring lights are to conclude thirty (30) minutes prior to dusk. (4) Rentals requiring lights must conclude no later than 11:00 p.m. (c) In cases where private security services are determined to be necessary by the Director, or his or her designee, it is the responsibility of the party renting the complex to provide the services, using a security service approved by the Director, or his or her designee. (d) Any party renting the complex is responsible for damages incurred during rental period and will be required to provide one million dollars ($1,000,000.00) liability and property damage insurance which includes the City of Cleveland as an additional insured. (e) Any party renting the complex will be required to provide emergency medical personnel for any athletic competition. (f) All proceeds from gate collections will go to the party renting the facility. (g) All concessions will be operated by the City of Cleveland or its designated vendor. (h) The Director shall deposit the fees and charges collected for the rental of the complex into the fund or funds designated to pay the costs of the general operation of the complex, the equipment and maintenance costs associated with maintaining the complex, and for improvements to the complex. The funds collected may be used for and are appropriated for these purposes. (i) After securing the necessary permit under Section 131.07 of these Codified Ordinances, the Director, or his or her designee, may allow the Cleveland Muny Football League and the Cleveland Metropolitan School District to rent athletic complexes for games, scrimmages, or practices, without being assessed the fees and charges specified in division (b) of this section. Section 3. That Section 131.35 of the Codified Ordinances of Cleveland, Ohio, 1976, as amended by Ordinance No. 459-14, passed June 9, 2014, is repealed. Section 4. That this ordinance is declared to be an emergency measure and, provided it receives the affirmative vote of two-thirds of all the members elected to Council, it shall take effect and be in force immediately upon its passage and approval by the Mayor; otherwise it shall take effect and be in force from and after the earliest period allowed by law. Referred to Directors of Public Works, Finance, Law; Committees on Municipal Services and Properties, Finance. </Junk></OrdRes>
</OrdResCollection>
